

Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Support, Project Management, Change Management, Apache Spark, Shell Scripting, Sqoop, HDFS, Yarn, Hive.



Current Designation: Software Engineer Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 6 Month(s)

Current Company: Accenture Solutions Pvt Ltd Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Location: Pune Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication]

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Pref. Location: Pune, Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hyderabad

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Support, Project Management, Change

Management, Data Modelling, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, Shell

Scripting, Sqoop, HDFS, Yarn, Hive, pyspark

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

Over 4+ years of total IT experience that includes 4 years as a Hadoop and Spark Developer.

Hands on experience in solutions for Big data using Hadoop, HDFS, Spark,, Hive, Sgoop.

Implemented Spark using Python and SparkSQL for transformation and faster processing of data.

Used SparkSQL over Hortonworks Hadoop Yarn to perform analytics on data in Hive.

Hands on experience with importing and exporting data from Relational databases to HDFS, Hive using Sqoop.

Experience in writing shell scripts for automating the Hive and Spark jobs.

Wrote Hive and SparkSQL queries for data analysis to meet the business requirements.

Involved in creating partitioning and bucketing for tables in Hive.

Good experience with Apache Phoenix for providing SQL like interface to HBASE .

Very good at data analysis, unit testing, debugging data quality issues.

Experience in Version Control Tools like Github.

Work Experience

Accenture Solutions Pvt Ltd as Software Engineer

May 2016 to Till Date

worked as a spark developer

Accenture as Software Engineer

May 2016 to May 2016

Accenture as Software Engineer

May 2016 to May 2016

Project 1: Standard Life May 2016 - Dec 2017

Standardlife is one of the largest health care plans provider in the USA. The project involves operations and maintenance of their legacy applications. This is a Maintenance and enhancement project for the Blue shield Group health insurance. BSC uses two different systems like Claims and Membership.

Responsibilities:

- Analysis of requirement specifications and prepare analysis documents. ? Daily, Weekly and Monthly status reporting for all the project stakeholders? Documenting the changes done.
- Providing Production support.
- Involved in Adhoc Desk support and maintaining Ad Hoc database.
- Acting as L1/L2 support member for the Membership cycle flow. Environment: COBOL, JCL, PUTTY, DB2

Project 2: Vodafone Jan 2018 - Nov 2020

Responsibilities:

- Have worked from scratch in two areas for a vodafone network provider.
- Fetched the data from data ware house and transferred it into new tables created in Hadoop. Those new tables are also segregated according to few data points like the offers used by customer, start date, end date, the frequency of using the offers, etc. This data was then analysed by the client to check which customers were taking the greatest number of offers and then providing those loyal customers with various new interesting offers exclusive to them.
- Have also worked with a different team, where we were working for the betterment of the service provided by the client. At this time, I was working with a third-party company, responsible for optimizing wireless solutions. We collected data from the third-party for different zones on hourly as well as daily basis and analysed the data to check if the network in a particular area was working optimally or not. This process required us to go through various data points to come to a conclusion, where the service had to be made better. We also informed the third-party for enhancing the network connection in that particular area. My work experience has been my major force and motivation for pursuing my postgraduation in data science
- Doing training on Big Data, Spark, Data Science.
- Part of Vodafone Idea development team and
- Optimizing Spark jobs and query of the jobs which are taking long time to run
- Have worked on 2 modules from scratch here.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from KIIT University, Bhuvaneshwar in 2016

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Apache Spark, HDFS, Yarn, Hive, Sqoop	
MySQL, Shell Scripting	
Linux (CentOS), Windows , GIT	
Python	3

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Hindi	Expert			
Bhojpuri	Proficient			

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time